# Zia Ur Rehman

Full Stack Developer

Contact No: +92 317 4557957

E-mail: ziaurrehmansandhu0@gmail.com
Website: <a href="https://ziaportfolio0.web.app/">https://ziaportfolio0.web.app/</a>

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/zia-ur-rehman-sandhu">https://www.linkedin.com/in/zia-ur-rehman-sandhu</a>

# **Professional Profile**

Result oriented, problem solver and resourceful software engineer with 2 years of experience in programming, managing and leading software development teams. I have worked on numerous projects and products from concept to completion. And my specialty is to take product's development from scratch to on field deployment.

# **Specialties & Skills:**

- Frontend Web (React Js, Next Js)
- Backend Web (Node js , Express Js, Flask)
- Database (Mongodb, Redis, MySql, firebase)
- Version Control (git, github)

# **Core Skills and Abilities**

- Skilled in developing user-friendly applications with clean code using React.js, Next.js, and Node.js.
- Proficient in optimizing and debugging applications for performance.
- Experienced in both independent and collaborative team environments, delivering effective solutions to clients.
- Strong communication skills, both verbal and written, including online and on field client support.
- Developed RESTful APIs in Node.js and proficient with version control systems like GIT
- Experienced with Material Design for enhancing web app usability
- Proficient in databases including MongoDB, Redis, Firebase and MySQL
- Experienced in parsing various data formats (XML, JSON, etc.) to support application functionality

### Education

### **B.S** (Computer Science)

University of Management and Technology

Graduated: 2024

### **Inter (Computer Science)**

Punjab Group of Colleges

Graduated: 2020

# **Employment History**

### UMT, Lahore

Full Stack Developer January 2024 - Present

- Responsible for developing and maintaining Next JS application using MySql.
- Collaborating with cross-functional teams to design and implement responsive and scalable solutions.
- Contributing to all phases of the software development lifecycle, from requirements gathering to deployment and maintenance.
- Implementing RESTful APIs and integrating with databases to optimize performance and user experience.
- Implement major functionalities in application to make it user friendly and meet business requirements.

### Codegenix

Full Stack Developer Remote Work September 2023 - Present

- Developed and maintained web applications using technologies such as React.js, Node.js, and Express.js.
- Collaborated remotely with a team to deliver responsive and user-friendly solutions.
- Implemented RESTful APIs and integrated third-party services for enhanced functionality.
- Implement real-time chat feature using web sockets in application.
- Utilized version control systems like Git to manage codebase efficiently.

#### **Smart SEO**

Wordpress, Laravel, PHP Developer Intern October 2022 - January 2023

- Designed and developed WordPress websites, implementing custom themes and plugins, for learning purpose.
- Contributed to Laravel and PHP projects, focusing on backend development and database management.

.

# **Projects**

### **Live Projects:**

## **X**apitx

Developed a comprehensive e-commerce platform using React.js and Node.js, integrating reat-time and user authentication.

URL: <a href="https://xapitx.com/">https://xapitx.com/</a>

### **Power Mart**

Developed a comprehensive e-commerce platform using React.js and Node.js, with admin panel.

URL: <a href="https://powermart.pk/">https://powermart.pk/</a>

### Livex

Collaborate with team to develop an educational website with live integrated zoom classes using Next.js and MySql URL: <a href="https://livex.tech/">https://livex.tech/</a>

### Paint App

Developed a mimic of MS Paint 2002 using react.js for a client. Here is the demo

URL: <a href="https://paint-app-beta.vercel.app/">https://paint-app-beta.vercel.app/</a>

### Web-Scrapper

Developed a next.js application that extracts all text from website and its all pages and user will be able to download a text files for all urls.

URL: <a href="https://web-scrapper-cheerio.vercel.app/">https://web-scrapper-cheerio.vercel.app/</a>

## **Practice Projects:**

### **Chat-App**

Created a real-time chat application using Socket.io and Next.js and Redis, allowing users to communicate in private and add other users through email.

URL: <a href="https://chitchat-demo.vercel.app/">https://chitchat-demo.vercel.app/</a>

### Blogger

Implemented a blogging platform with CRUD functionality using Express.js and MongoDB, enabling users to create, edit, and delete blog posts.

URL: https://demo-blogger.vercel.app/